## Yogesh Bendre

07.yogesh@gmail.com

**+91 94821 49247** 

in linkedin.com/in/yogesh-bendre

### Summary

#5+ years of industry experience.

# Worked on various Machine Learning projects.

# MS (IIT Madras): Experience of Machine Learning Research.

# CGPA: 9.8 /10 and Best MS Thesis Award.

# ML, Java, Python, Virtualization, Algorithms, Data Structures, Writing Skills.

### **Experience**



MTS Level 3 Aug 2017- Present

**VMware** 

Developed project Sherlock which offers an ML-based web service. Teams can register vCenter setup and Sherlock will keep monitoring for issues. Used Machine Learning for detecting abnormal growths in metrics like memory, disk space, etc. which can cause failures much later in time. Detecting the exact time of growth can point to the window of cause. Used docker container for scalability. Automated multi-node vCenter monitoring including analysis report.

**Technology:** Python, Django, Docker Containers

**Impact:** Teams needed more human hours for monitoring with the increasing vCenter scale.

With Sherlock, most of the heavy lifting of monitoring and analysis is done automatically.

- Acquired expertise on log analysis product called "Log Insight" and automated the log analysis process. This module went as a part of Sherlock.
- Received Spot Award for the module.



MTS Level 2 Jul 2015 - Jul 2017

**VMware** 2 years 1 month

Developed project Galilio that clusters hundreds of error logs on the fly into unique issues. Offered Galilio as a web portal where data can be uploaded and results are presented. Due to the lack of any labelled information and the dynamic nature of data, pretraining of models was not possible. Used unsupervised clustering to solve this problem.

Technology: Unsupervised Clustering, Dimensionality Reduction (PCA), Python, Bottle

Impact: Reduced the time taken for debugging from a couple of days to a few minutes.

Received Spot Award for the project.

Worked on other virtualization-based projects



MTS Level 1 Jul 2013 - Jun 2015

**VMware** 2 years

- Acquired knowledge about the virtualization domain and internal automation techniques.
- Developed server crash prediction engine using past data.
- Filed patents in the domain of virtualization.

#### **Education**



#### Indian Institute of Technology, Madras

2010 - 2013

MS, Machine Learning, CGPA: 9.8 / 10

- · Acquired knowledge about Machine Learning.
- Worked on the research project to improve the time taken in parameter tuning for the kernel functions.
- Invented a method to compute the right set of parameters for kernel functions using the manifold structure of the data which is much faster than the traditional method. Reduced the time complexity of SVM model selection from O(n^3) to O(n^2).
- Technology: Machine Learning, Matlab
- Received the Best MS Thesis Award for the research work.



# Walchand College of Engineering (Shivaji University, Maharashtra)

2005 - 2009

BE (CSE), Computer Science and Engineering, 70.58%

• Implemented a virus detection technique using data mining with Naive Bayes classifier. Achieved high detection rate on unseen virus files without having the explicite signatures.

Technology: Machine Learning, Visual C++

Implemented working SMS based home lighting control system.

Technology: Java and Visual C++



#### **HSC Board, Pune**

2004 - 2005

XII, Science, 93.00%



#### SSC Board, Pune

2002 - 2003

X, Science, 90.66%

#### **Skills**



Java (Proficient) • Python (Comfortable) • GIT (Used) • Perforce (Used) • Machine Learning

#### **Certifications**

# Data Science Specialization by Johns Hopkins University on Coursera • Coursera Course Certificates

**Deep Learning Nanodegree • Udacity** 

Jan 2019 - Present